Guide to the John B. Oakes Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Arranged Subject Files
  - Subseries III.6: Clubs, Awards, Honors, Etc.
    - America the Beautiful (Box 58)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 58)
    - American Newspaper Publishers Association (Box 58)
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 58)
    - American Press Institute (Box 58)
    - American Society of Newspaper Editors (Box 58)
    - American Wilderness Alliance (Box 58)
    - America’s Watch/ Helsinki Watch (Box 59)
    - Aspen Seminar, 8/29-9/3/70 (Box 59)
    - Axe-Houghton Foundation (Box 59)
    - Beamish, Richard (Box 59)
    - Brearly School (Box 59)
    - Center for Communication: Population Resource Center (Box 59)
    - Century Club (Box 59)
    - Channel Thirteen (Box 59)
    - Chatham College Board of Trustees (Box 59)
    - Coast Alliance (Box 59)
    - Collegiate School (Box 60)
    - Columbia University (Box 60)
    - Columbia University Oral History, (2 folders ) (Box 60)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists (Box 60)
    - Conservation Foundation (Box 60)
    - Conservation Law Foundation of New England (Box 60)
    - Cosmos Club (Box 60)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 60)
    - Council on Learning Advisory Board (Box 60)
    - Defenders of Wildlife (Box 60)
    - Editor in Residence (Box 60)
    - Environmental Bond Act Committee (Box 60)
    - Environmental Project in Central America (Box 60)
    - Fellowship in Israel for Arab-Jewish Youth, Inc. (Box 60)
    - Fisk University (Box 61)
    - Forum Institute Prevention-Nuclear War, 1983 (Box 61)
    - French-American Foundation (Box 61)
    - Friends of the Earth (Box 61)
    - Garden Club of America (Box 61)
    - Global 2000 (Box 61)
    - Harper’s Ferry Meeting, 1/8/80 (Box 61)
    - Heckinger Institute (Box 61)
    - Institute for Policy Studies US/USSR Conference (Box 61)
    - League of Conservation Voters (Box 61)
    - MacArthur Foundation Global Issues (Box 61)
    - Moniter-NYT Foundation (Box 61)
    - National Audubon Society (Box 61)
    - National Environmental Leadership Council (Box 61)
    - National News Council (Twentieth Century Fund) (Box 62)
    - National Parks and Conservation Assoc./ National Parks Service (Box 62)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 62)
    - NYC Police Foundation, Inc. Board of Trustees (Box 62)
    - National Public Lands Advisory Council (Bureau of Land Management, US Dept. of the Interior) (Box 63)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 63)
    - NYC Audubon Society (Box 63)
    - New York City Urban Fellowship (Box 63)
    - New York Foundation (Box 63)
    - New York Society (Box 64)
    - NYS Conservation Council, Inc. (Box 64)
    - New York State Environmental 2000 Program (Box 64)
    - NYU Council (Box 64)
    - Neiman Foundation (Box 64)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Association (Box 64)
    - Princeton University Advisory Council/Hillel/Whig-Clio (Box 64)
    - Princeton University Advisory Council (Box 64)
    - Princeton University Alumni Weekly, 1952 (Box 64)
    - Princeton University CAP Right Wing Alumni Publication and Rebuttal (Box 64)
    - Princeton University Sheldon Fund, 1948-49 (Box 64)
    - The Queen’s College College Building Expansion (Box 64)
    - Rhodes American Oxonian (Box 64)
    - Rhodes Association of American Rhodes Scholars (Box 64)
    - Rhodes Class Letter (JBO Class Secretary) (Box 65)
    - Rhodes Reunions in UK et al. Rhodes Class Reunions (Box 65)
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust (Box 65)
    - Roundtable (Box 65)
    - Save-the-Redwoods League (Box 65)
    - Sierra Club (Box 65)
    - Sigma Delta Chi (Box 66)
    - State Charities Aid Assoc. Board of Managers Member, 1937-1957 (Box 66)
    - Temple Emanu-El (Box 66)
    - United Nations Association of the USA (Environmental Group) (Box 66)
    - University of Hartford (Box 66)
    - Trilateral Commission (Box 66)
    - Vineyard Conservation Society (Box 66)
    - Warburg Museum 5th Ave. Preservation (Box 66)
    - Wilderness Society (Box 66)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation (Box 66)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation and Papers (Box 66)
    - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars (Box 66)
    - World Resources Institute (Box 66)
  - Subseries III.7: Family Papers
    - George W. Oakes (Box 67)
    - George W. Oakes Estate Etc. (Box 67)
    - George W. Oakes Memorial Plaque at Whig Hall, Princeton U. (Box 67)
    - Oakes, G.W. Bequests—Princeton (Box 67)
    - Oakes Memorial F.S.S.C (Box 67)
    - Oakes Memorial—Queen’s College (Box 67)
    - Oakes, George W. Memorial Pamphlet (Box 67)
    - GWOO/ASO/ CHK Curtis Public Ledger (Box 67)
    - GWOO/NBO Knoxville and Chattanooga (Box 67)
    - George Washington Ochs-Oakes Mayor of Chattanooga/Current History (Box 67)
    - George Washington Ochs-Oakes Negotiations to buy Public Ledger (Box 67)
    - George Washington Ochs-Oakes Speeches/Correspondence (Box 67)
    - Current History Magazine, Dec. 1931 (Box 68)
    - George W. Ochs-Oakes (Box 68)
    - George W. Ochs-Oakes Unsorted Correspondence (Box 68)
    - George W. Ochs-Oakes Clippings (Box 68)
    - George W. Oches-Oakes Paris and Philadelphia pre-Ledger (Box 68)
    - George W. Ochs-Oakes Public Ledger and ASO (Box 68)
    - George W. Ochs-Oakes On Zionism (Box 68)
    - Ochs-Oakes George W. Papers (Box 68)
  - Subseries III.8: Family Papers: Ochs/Talimer Papers
    - Adler, General Julius Ochs (Box 69)
    - Ochs Family (Box 69)
    - Ochs, Adolph (Box 69)
    - Ochs, Martin and A. Shelby (Tenn.) (Box 69)
    - Talimer Estate (2) (Box 69)
    - Family letters/papers (Box 69)
- Series IV: Writings
  - Subseries IV.1: New York Times Op-Ee Articles and Responces
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.1: Acid Rain
      - Acid Rain’s Political Poison, 4/8/85 (Box 70)
      - More Inaction on Acid Rain, 1/12/86 (Box 70)
      - Background File: Acid Rain/Clean Air (Box 70)
        [See also Op-Eds of 7/8/77, 8/31/81, 10/29/82, 4/8/85, 1/21/86, 10/15/89]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.2: Adirondacks
      - Adirondack S.O.S. 10/29/88 (Box 70)
      - Will Albany Save Our Heritage?, 3/31/90 (Box 70)
      - Last Stand for the Adirondacks, 6/19/92 (Box 70)
      - Goodbye Adirondacks, 6/24/93 (Box 70)
      - Background File: Adirondacks (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.3: Alaska
      - The Great Alaska Rip-Off (includes other reprints and senators’ letters), 8/31/78 (Box 70)
      - Lost Weekend, 10/24/78 (Box 70)
      - Rescuing Alaska’s Lands, 12/8/78 (Box 70)
      - Heating Up on Alaska, 11/30/79 (Box 70)
      - Andrus to the Rescue, 2/20/80 (Box 70)
      - Periling Alaska’s Lands, 9/23/80 (Box 70)
      - Background File: Alaska (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.4: Anderson, John B.
      - The Anderson Principle, 3/20/80 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.5: Arafat
      - Arafat’s Card, 3/18/84 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.6: Argentina
      - Argentina’s Terror, 5/15/79 (Box 70)
      - Vanished in Argentina, 5/16/79 (Box 70)
      - Agony in Argentina, 6/29/79 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.7: Arias Plan
      - Avoid Sabotage of the Arias Plan, 10/27/87 (Box 70)
      - Quit Sabotaging the Arias Plan, 1/3/88 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.8: Austria
      - The Man in the Middle, 4/14/78 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.9: Beame
      - Mayor Beame’s Smoggy View, 7/8/77 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.10: Bork
      - Why All the Smears by Bork’s Allies, 9/22/87 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.11: Brazil
      - Brazil’s Nuclear Drive, 4/25/77 (Box 70)
      - Authoritarianism, Brazilian Style, 4/26/77 (Box 70)
      - Brazil’s 2 Nations, 4/27/77 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.12: Bulgaria
      - A Chip off the Soviet Bloc, 9/1/82 (Box 70)
      - Bulgaria, on the U.S, 9/12/82 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.13: Bush, George H.W.
      - Bush vs. Bush on the Environment, 10/15/88 (Box 71)
      - Bush’s Calumnies: A Dangerous Game, 11/5/88 (Box 71)
      - Bush’s Shell Game, 1/12/89 (Box 71)
      - Early Bush, Early Folly, 3/1/89 (Box 71)
      - Bush’s “Environmentalists”: Who’s Watt, and Why, 4/29/89 (Box 71)
      - Bush Nominates Watt II, 11/8/89 (Box 71)
      - Bush in Panama: A Tragicomedy, 1/26/90 (Box 71)
      - Mr. Bush, Lean on the Lithuanians, 4/21/90 (Box 71)
      - An Environmentalist? Bush? Forget It., 5/8/92 (Box 71)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.14: Camp David Accords
      - “The Apple of Peace” and Begin, 8/18/77 (Box 71)
      - A Talk with Begin, 8/25/77 (Box 71)
      - Begin: “Everyone Knows He’s the Boss, 8/26/77 (Box 71)
      - Assad Favors Peace with Israel, But Rejects any Closer Relations, 8/29/77 (Box 71)
      - Begin, On the Spot, 11/22/77 (Box 71)
      - In the Sphinx’s Shadow, 12/14/77 (Box 71)
      - Camp David Accords—A Shaky Framework, 10/6/78 (Box 71)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.15: Carter
      - A New Beginning, A New Year, 12/31/76 (Box 71)
      - A Conversation with Mr. Sorensen, 1/14/77 (Box 71)
      - That Questionnaire…An Unrequested Reply, 3/1//77 (Box 71)
      - On-the-Spot Morality, 10/6/77 (Box 71)
      - Enough of Mr. Young, 8/3/78 (Box 71)
      - Turning Point on Water Policy, 10/23/78 (Box 71)
      - “Moment of Truth”, 12/14/78 (Box 71)
      - America’s Loss of Face, 12/29/78 (Box 71)
      - Victories for “Them”, 3/1/79 (Box 71)
      - Carter’s Synthetic Program, 8/16/79 (Box 71)
      - Carter’s Ironic Choice, 10/16/79 (Box 71)
      - Carter’s Cold War Tactic, 1/22/80 (Box 71)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.16: Castro
      - Castro Bends a Little, 11/6/86 (Box 72)
      - Castro’s “Rights” Policy, 11/7/85 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.17: Central America
      - Central American Folly, 11/26/82 (Box 72)
      - A Call for Deescalation, 7/22/83 (Box 72)
      - Ripe for Revolution, 7/23/83 (Box 72)
      - Casual Latin Policy, 1/28/84 (Box 72)
      - Greening Central America -- Background File: Central America, 4/20/88 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.18: Charlotte Street
      - The Charlotte Street Rush -- Background File: Charlotte Street, 11/24/78 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.19: Chile
      - Pinochet in No Rush Part I, 5/3/79 (Box 72)
      - Chile’s “Chicago” Pill Part II, 5/4/79 (Box 72)
      - “Law and Order” in Chile, 5/6/79 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.20: China
      - China’s People Problem, 8/29/80 (Box 72)
      - China’s Good Life, 8/30/80 (Box 72)
      - China’s American Card, 8/31/80 (Box 72)
      - China’s New Pragmatism, 9/1/80 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.21: Cities
      - Conscience of the Nation, 11/11/75 (Box 72)
      - Now, It is the Cities’ Turn, 11/11/77 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.22: Clark
      - Clark’s Low Wattage, 10/18/83 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.23: Czechoslovakia
      - How Czechs Get Along, 5/5/78 (Box 72)
      - In Prague, Still No Thaw, 2/11/89 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.24: Dams/Hydroelectric Power
      - Thinking Small, 3/23/77 (Box 72)
      - Taking the Waters -- Background File: Dams/Hydroelectric Power, 5/17/77 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.25: Democrats
      - Democrats’ Nest Egg (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.26: Developers
      - Developers Never Say Die, 6/8/87 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.27: Ellison Case*
      - Background File: Ellison Case: “Whistle Blower Nuclear Power Plant”, 6/9/77, (1 Video 3, tapes ) (Box 73)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.28: El Salvador
      - End Run on El Salvador, 2/24/83 (Box 73)
      - In El Salvador, a Dance of Death, 12/12/84 (Box 73)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.29: Environmentalism
      - Battle for the Environment, 12/2/76 (Box 73)
      - “The Year of the Coast”, 3/2/79 (Box 73)
      - Saving the Web of Life, 12/28/79 (Box 73)
      - Back to Environmentalism, 11/10/86 (Box 73)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.30: Falklands
      - Phony Falklands Issues, 5/23/82 (Box 73)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.31: Fur
      - “Trapped”, 2/13/79 (Box 73)
      - Fur Coat Trap, 12/25/86 (Box 73)
        [Background File: Furs/Trapping]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.32: G.O.P.
      - G.O.P. Platform—Grounds for Worry, 9/25/84 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.33: Guatemala (Blake Case)
      - 2 Who Disappeared in Guatemala, Forever?, 1/6/86 (Box 74)
        [Background File: Blake Case 1985-6]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.34: Haig
      - Haig’s Wrong Signals, 4/3/81 (Box 74)
      - Some History for Haig, 4/6/82 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.35: Hodel
      - Hodel Squanders Our Birthright, 5/12/87 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.36: Honduras
      - Treating Honduras as a Vassal State, 1/11/85 (Box 74)
      - What Honduras Wants from Us, 1/14/85 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.37: Hungary
      - Hungary’s Leader Voices Confidence in Détente, 6/10/78 (Box 74)
      - Hungary Reaches Westward, 7/7/78 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.38: India
      - An Analysis of the Indian Election (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.39: Iran
      - The Persian Mind, 9/30/75 (Box 74)
      - Tightrope in Iran, 1/12/79 (Box 74)
      - Iran’s Tidal Wave, 1/23/795 (Box 74)
      - Learning from the Crisis, 12/11/79 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.40: Iraq
      - Saying No to No-Win War (NY Newsday), 1/11/91 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.41: Ireland
      - The British Dimension, 10/6/79 (Box 74)
      - D’Amato’s Irish Fling, 12/18/80 (Box 74)
      - To American Friends of Harrod’s Bombing, 12/26/83 (Box 74)
        [Background File: Ireland]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.42: Jacob Riis Park
      - Green, Not Greenbacks at Jacob Riis Park, 6/14/88 (Box 74)
        [Background File: Jacob Riis Park]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.43: Japan
      - Can Japan Survive its Own Success, 11/30/70 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.44: Koch
      - An Ordinary Guy, 9/17/77 (Box 74)
      - Koch’s Chutzpah, 6/21/83 (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.45: Korea
      - Yankee, Please Stay a Little While, 11/23/70 (Box 75)
      - All Quiet Along the Other DMZ, 11/24/70 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.46: Libya
      - More than Libya was Ground Zero, 5/8/86 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.47: McGovern
      - The Next Four Years (Acknowledgment) McGovern Endorsement, 9/28/72 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.48: Marcos
      - The House of Marcos, 7/4/80 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.49: Martha’s Vineyard
      - A Plea to Stop, Look, and Listen (Vineyard Gazette), 7/27/71 (Box 75)
      - The Vineyard’s Grapes of Wrath (On the Vineyard), 7/80 (Box 75)
      - Island Faces Array of Environmental Threats (Vineyard Gazette), 9/2/94 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.50: Mayor of NYC
      - More than a Mayor, 11/2/77 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.51: Meese
      - Not Only Meese is Now on Trial, 2/4/85 (Box 75)
      - Meese’s Record on Failure, 11/17/87 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.52: Mexico
      - Mexico’s Leader, Outlining Plans, Sees a Challenge in National Crisis, 2/1/77 (Box 75)
      - Mexico’s New Regime I, 2/10/77 (Box 75)
      - Mexico’s New Regime II, 2/11/77 (Box 75)
      - Ferment in the Americas, 2/26/77 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.53: Middle East*
      - Background Files Middle East (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.54: Morocco
      - In Morocco, a Fire is Slowly Burning, 4/28/84 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.55: Moynihan
      - JBO Opposition to NYT Moynihan Endorsement, 9/1976 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.56: MX Missile
      - MX: Tick, Tick, Tick, 10/21/80 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.57: National Parks
      - Bye, National Parks, 6/7/85 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.58: Nicaragua
      - “Fraud” in Nicaragua, 11/15/84 (Box 75)
      - U.S. Aid is Misguided, 3/7/86 (Box 75)
      - The Wrong Risk in Nicaragua, 2/11/87 (Box 75)
      - To Ortega: Throw the Election, 2/24/90 (Box 75)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.59: NYT State of the City Series*
      - State of City (acknowledgements), 5/11-5/25/75 (Box 76)
      - Background File: NYC “State of the City” Editorial Series”, 1975 (Box 76)
      - PAC (Political Action Committees): (Box 76)
      - The PAC-Man’s Game—Eating Legislators, 9/6/84 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.60: Palestinians
      - Defying the P.L.O., 12/21/77 (Box 76)
      - West Bank Voices, 9/9/77 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.61: Peru
      - Peru at Mid-Passage, 4/19/79 (Box 76)
      - Peru’s Rocky Road, 4/20/79 (Box 76)
      - Peru’s Time of Transition, 4/21/79 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.62: Polluters
      - To Vote Against Polluters, 10/29/82 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.63: Pork Barrel Politics
      - Boondoggles, 6/9/77 (Box 76)
      - The Pork Barrel Challenge, 7/21/77 (Box 76)
      - Pork—U.S. Prime, 7/29/81 (Box 76)
      - Highway Robbery, 12/16/81 (Box 76)
      - Lame Ducks, With Pork, 1/6/83 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.64: Powell, Adam Clayton
      - Past editorials in clip file (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.65: Press
      - Confidence in the Press, 5/5/76 (Box 76)
      - Dwindling Faith in the Press, 5/24/78 (Box 76)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.66: Reagan
      - For Reagan, A Ticking Ecological Time Bomb, 1/20/81 (Box 76)
      - An Insecurity Blanket, 2/17/81 (Box 76)
      - Reaganvironmentalism, 5/18/81 (Box 76)
      - The Ketchikan Caper, 5/19/81 (Box 76)
      - Foreign Nonpolicy, 7/8/81 (Box 76)
        [Background File: Arms Race and Arms Sales]
      - Reagan Making Bad Start on Nature, 8/31/81 (Box 77)
      - The Reagan Hoax, 11/7/81 (Box 77)
      - Tragicomedy: Act 1, 12/10/81 (Box 77)
      - Tragicomedy: Act 2, 2/4/82 (Box 77)
      - Reagan’s Path to War, 8/3/83 (Box 77)
      - Reagan’s Slide to War, 9/29/83 (Box 77)
      - Reagan’s Shaking Fist, 1/9/84 (Box 77)
      - Reagan’s Version of the Truth, 7/9/84 (Box 77)
      - Mr. Reagan’s Bombs, 8/8/84 (Box 77)
      - Environment-Buster Reagan, 10/20/84 (Box 77)
      - Mr. Reagan’s Flim-Flamming, 4/17/85 (Box 77)
      - Reagan’s Brezhnev Doctrine, 5/20/85 (Box 77)
      - Reagan Keeps Gearing Up to Overthrow the Sandanistas, 8/5/85 (Box 77)
      - Reagan Isn’t Buoying Freedom Abroad, 4/6/86 (Box 77)
      - Reagan Legitimizes Botha, 5/29/86 (Box 77)
      - Why is the Iran Deal a Surprise? Reagan Has Long Been Deceptive, 12/17/86 (Box 78)
      - What the President Should Do Next? Consider Stepping Down, 3/1//87 (Box 78)
      - Reagan Fails the Country, 8/11/87 (Box 78)
      - Will Reagan Imperil Public Lands, 2/17/88 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.67: Rumania
      - On Rumania, the West, and the East, 8/4/82 (Box 78)
      - Hard-Pressed Rumania Looks to Washington, 8/5/82 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.68: Silent Spring
      - Silent Spring, For Kids, 3/30/89 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.69: South Africa
      - In South Africa, A Gathering Storm, 7/18/86 (Box 78)
      - The Manacles on South Africa’s Media, 7/23/86 (Box 78)
      - Botha’s Last Chance, 7/31/86 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.70: Soviet Union
      - Orlov’s Crime, 2/10/83 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.71: Star Wars
      - Out of Star Wars and Back to Earth, 10/29/86 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.72: Staten Island
      - Whistle-Blowing on Staten Island, 1/8/80 (Box 78)
        [Background File: Staten Island]
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.73: Taiwan
      - Taiwan, Buffeted by Friend and Foe, 8/6/80 (Box 78)
      - Taiwan’s Identity Crisis, 8/7/80 (Box 78)
      - In Taiwan, Pluses and Minuses, 8/8/80 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.74: Trilateral Commission
      - The Trilateral Way, 4/10/80 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.75: Vietnam
      - The 3 Wars of Vietnam, 4/13/67 (Box 78)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.76: Watt
      - Watt’s Very Wrong, 12/31/80 (Box 79)
      - Background Files: Watt Book (2); Watt Editorials (by others); Watt Record (Box 79)
      - Background Files: Watt Research; Watt Secretary of the Interior (Box 80)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.77: Westway
      - Westway Panic Button, 12/19/78 (Box 81)
      - Transit, Not Westway, 11/15/79 (Box 81)
      - Mr. Carey, Westway is the Wrong Way to Go, 3/10/81 (Box 81)
      - Westway: Bad Way; Trade-In: Best Way, 10/21/82 (Box 81)
      - Westwaygate, 3/21/83 (Box 81)
      - Westway, Governor? No Way!, 6/6/83 (Box 81)
      - Way Beyond Westway, 11/30/83 (Box 81)
      - Instead, Call it Wasteway, 6/2/84 (Box 81)
      - Westway Red Herring, 1/19/85 (Box 81)
      - Hell-for-Broke on Westway, 2/16/85 (Box 81)
      - A Westway Trade-in, or Not? Yes—For Transit, 9/18/85 (Box 81)
      - Post-Westway Political Cares, 10/18/85 (Box 81)
      - Daughter of Westway: A New Fiasco, 7/8/88 (Box 81)
      - Background Files: Westway (Box 81)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.78: Whaling
      - Japan, Swallow Hard and Stop Whaling, 1/19/83 (Box 81)
      - Background File: Whaling (Box 81)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.79: Yugoslavia
      - Strains, Rivalries, Disparities, 6/24/82 (Box 81)
      - Yugoslavia(s), 6/25/82 (Box 81)
  - Subseries IV.2: Editorial Books
    - Sub-subseries IV.2.1: Preliminary
      - Preliminary Materials (Box 82)
    - Sub-subseries IV.2.2: Book: The United States
      - Chapter 1: The Presidency (Box 82)
      - Chapter 2: Constitutional Liberties (Box 82)
      - Chapter 3: Civil Rights (Box 82)
      - Chapter 4: McCarthyism (Box 82)
      - Chapter 5: The Washington Scene (Box 82)
      - Chapter 6: The State of New York (Box 83)
      - Chapter 7: The City of New York (Box 83)
      - Chapter 8: Our Environment (Box 83)
      - Chapter 9: Into the Space Age (Box 83)
      - Chapter 10: The American Scene (Box 83)
      - Chapter 11: The Press and the Times (part 1: the press part 2: the Times) (Box 83)
      - Chapter 12: Men of Our Time (Box 83)
    - Sub-subseries IV.2.3: Book: The World
      - Chapter 1: The Second World War (Box 84)
      - Chapter 2: The Cold War (Box 84)
      - Chapter 3: The Korean War (Box 84)
      - Chapter 5: The Atom in War and Peace (Box 84)
      - Chapter 6: The United Nations (Box 85)
      - Chapter 7: The World at Large (Box 85)
      - Chapter 8: Men of the World (Box 85)
  - Subseries IV.3: Printed
    - The Edge of Freedom (Box 86)
    - Social Responsibility of the News Press (2) (Box 86)
    - The State of the City (Box 86)
  - Subseries IV.4: Foreign Travel and Related Article
    - 1952 (Box 87)
    - Reports on Trips Abroad, 1957 (Box 87)
    - Africa: Photos Carnegie Corp. Grant re: book Edge of Freedom, 1959 (Box 87)
    - Brazil Conference on World Tensions, 8/6-12/62 (Box 87)
    - Trip to Pakistan/India/Vietnam, Feb./March 1967 (Box 87)
    - Material for Article on India, Feb./March 1967 (Box 87)
    - Material for Article on Vietnam, Feb/March 1967 (Box 87)
    - Trip, 1968 (Box 88)
    - Trip to England, June 1968 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Japan, Oct-Nov. 1970 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Korea, 10/14-17/70 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Israel and Egypt, 5/13-6/4/72 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Paris, Bonn, Prague, Budapest, Fall 1973 (Box 88)
    - Trip to London, Amsterdam, Brussels, Paris, March 1974 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Jamaica, Feb. 1974 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Iran, Sept. 1975 (Box 88)
    - Alaska, 1975/1979 (Box 88)
    - Alaska, 1978/80 (Box 88)
    - Trip to Brazil, March-April 1977 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Mexico, Jan. 1977 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Israel, Jordan, Syria, Lebanon, France, August 1977 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Czechoslovakia, March 1978 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Austria, March 1978 (Box 89)
    - Hungary, 1978 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Hungary, March-April-June 1978 (Box 89)
    - Rhodesia, 1978 (Box 89)
    - Peru March, 1979 (Box 89)
    - Trip to Peru, March 1979 (Box 90)
    - Trip to Chile, March-April 1979 (Box 90)
    - Trip to Argentina, April 1979 (Box 90)
    - Trip to Ireland and England, August 1979 (Box 90)
    - Chile, 1979 (Box 90)
    - Philippines -- Names and Addresses—Communications, 1980 (Box 90)
    - Trip to China, Early May 1980 (Box 90)
    - Trip to Taiwan, late May-early June 1980 (Box 90)
    - Taiwan -- Names, Addresses—Communications, 1980 (Box 90)
    - Taiwan, 1980 (Box 90)